Guide to the Irving I. Herzberg photograph collection BCMS.0056
Brooklyn Collection
Irving I. Herzberg photograph collection
1949-1989
1949-2002
Brooklyn Collection
Herzberg, Irving I.
BCMS.0056
65.8 Linear Feet 36 small boxes, 22 manuscript boxes, 19 flat boxes, 5 record cartons
The digitized portions of this collection are available on our digital collections under the call number prefix HERZ.
Materials from the life and work of photographer Irving Herzberg (1915-1991). Items include photographs, color slides, negatives, cassettes, and documents. Subjects include New York City's Jewish communities, street scenes, transit, architecture, and Coney Island. Also included are images from travels across the United States, Europe, Israel, and Egypt.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
The majority of the materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
A portion of this collection was gifted by Irving Herzberg over several years starting in the early 1960s. Additional portions were gifts of Helen Herzberg, 1992 and 1995. Additional items transfered from the Jewish Museum, 2005.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series:
Series 1: Photographs is arranged in three sub-series by image size. Sub-series 1.1 is arranged alphabetically by subject, with the exception of Hasidim of Williamsburg, which appears at the end of the sub-series and is arranged by subject. Sub-series 1.2 is partially arranged by subject or exhibit. Sub-series 1.3 is not arranged.
Seies 2: Slides is arranged by subject. Slides reflect the original order as they appeared in slide carousels arranged by Irving Herzberg.
Series 3: Negatives is arranged in booklets by negative number, in numerical order. Booklets and negatives arranged in the booklets are presumably in original order.
Series 4: Audiovisual is arranged by subject.
Series 5: Documents is arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
Irving Herzberg was born May 3, 1915, in Varel, Germany as Iwan Herzberg to parents Sally (Saul) and Gertrude. Herzberg attended elementary school at the local synagogue and later enrolled in Varel's Oberrealschule (secondary school). He received his first camera at age 13 as a gift for his bar mitzvah. His grandfather owned a local cleaning and dyeing factory, which his father took over and later sold. Fleeing the rise of Adolf Hitler, Herzberg left Germany in 1935, followed by his parents in 1939. After arriving in New York City, Herzberg attempted work as a dyer, but the business was unsuccessful. He found employment at a company that imported musical novelties and worked as a self-employed photographer.
Herzberg spent more than 50 years photographing New York. He founded the Trump Village Camera Club, and using his home's bathroom as a darkroom, produced prints to exhibit across the city. He created several series including Faces Across the Aisle: Subway Glimpses, The Hasidim of Williamsburg, Coney Island....My Backyard, and Jewish Life on Ocean Avenue which was commissioned by the American Jewish Congress. Starting in the 1970s Herzberg began traveling across the United States, Europe, Egypt and Israel. Some of the photographs were presented in 1975 as a slideshow with accompanying music and narration, called Let's Go West, performed at the Brooklyn Public Library's Brighton Beach branch, Trump Village Camera Club and the Men's Club of the Temple Beth Abraham.
Irving Herzberg was a frequent patron of the Brooklyn Public Library's Brooklyn Collection and began selling his photographs to the library in the 1960s. He died on May 17, 1991. From November 1995- January 1996 the library hosted Irving I. Herzberg: A Vision of Brooklyn (1950-1989), a retrospective of his work featuring prints given to the library during his life, and posthumously by his wife, Helen Herzberg.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of black-and-white gelatin silver photographs, color slides, negatives, cassettes, and documents from photographer Irving Herzberg, the bulk of which covers New York City and his travels across the United States, Europe, Israel, and Egypt. The photographs date from 1952-1989 and include images from his various series including Faces Across the Aisle: Subway Glimpses, The Hasidim of Williamsburg, Jewish Life on Ocean Avenue, and Coney Island....My Backyard. Many photographs include a stamp or paper affixed to the back with the exhibit location and date. Please note that dates usually represent the date of exhibition, not when the photograph was taken or printed. Most prints also include a corresponding negative number handwritten on the back.
Slides include images of Herzberg's travels, both in the United States and internationally. Slides were originally arranged in slide carousels by Herzberg for the presentation of Let's Go West. Slides have been rehoused in binders but represent Herzberg's original arrangement. The Let's Go West presentation also included music and Herzberg's own narration on cassettes, which are available in Series 4: Audiovisual. Negatives are large format, housed in small booklets created by Herzberg, with 2-12 negatives per booklet. Information handwritten in the booklets often includes dates, camera settings, titles, and darkroom instructions. Many negatives have a corresponding print in Series 1: Photographs.
Documents include printed and handwritten indexes to Herzberg's work, created by Brooklyn Public Library librarians. Documents also include exhibit invitations, promotional materials, and invitation lists. Materials for Irving I. Herzberg: A Vision of Brooklyn (1950-1989), have been foldered separately. Oversize exhibit materials are foldered with Sub-series 1.3: Photographs and Exhibit Materials.
Related Materials
George Aptecker Collection, CBHM.0003
Jamel Shabazz photograph collection, BCMS.0055
John D. Morrell Photograph Collection, ARC.005
Larry Racioppo Collection, BCMS.0053
Lucille Fornasieri-Gold photographs, 2008.013
Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Ocean Avenue (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Subways -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Hasidim -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Jewish neighborhoods -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Architecture -- New York (State); Travel photography; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Color slides; Negatives (Photographs); Israel; Travel -- Egypt; Europe -- Description and travel; Street photography -- New York (State) -- New York; Portraits; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Jews, German -- New York (State) -- New York
- Series 1: Photographs
  - Sub-series 1.1: 8x10 Photographs
    - Animals, 1952-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Borough Hall Steps, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bridges, 1955-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Botanical Garden, 1953, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Eagle, Picketing, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn Waterfront, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Public Library, 1953-1966, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Buildings: General, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Buildings: Home, 1958-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Buildings: Government, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Children: General, 1955-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Children with Pets, 1963-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Churches: Brooklyn, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Coney Island: Amusement Area, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Coney Island: Assembly of Jahweh Baptism, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Coney Island: Beach, 1958-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
    - Coney Island: Boardwalk, 1958-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
    - Coney Island: Buildings, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Coney Island: Children, 1961-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Coney Island: Children at the Beach, 1957-1975 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Coney Island: Children on the Boardwalk, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Coney Island: Creek Geology Cleanup, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Coney Island: Fire, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Coney Island: Nathan's, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Coney Island: People, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Coney Island: Polar Bear Club, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Coney Island: Seniors, 1952-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
    - Country Side, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Department Stores, 1958-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Myrtle Avenue El, 1958-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ellis Island, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Europe, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fire Department: Fires, 1958, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Fort Greene Park Monument, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gowanus Canal, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Grand Army Plaza Monument, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Guggenheim Museum, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Buildings, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Children, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Duplicates, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Families, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Groups of People, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Holidays, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Rabbis, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Schools, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Temple Exterior, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Temple Interior, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Washington Cemetery, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Community, Ocean Parkway: Wedding, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Lakeside, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lewisohn Stadium: Audience Members, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Lewisohn Stadium: Performers, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Magnolia Tree, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Men in Uniform, 1955-1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Men Working, 1951-1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - People, 1950-1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Portraits: Headshots and Character Studies, 1952-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Portraits: Head Shots and Character Studies, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Portraits: Character Studies, Vaudeville Actor, 1950-1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Plane Crash, 7th Avenue, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Prospect Park, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Prospect Place Market, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Herzberg Self Portrait, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Shoeshine Stand, Joseph Caramanica, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Signage, 1968-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Staten Island Ferry, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Faces Across the Aisle: Subway Glimpses, circa 1950-1960 (Box 3, Folder 11-19)
    - Tattoo Shops, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Theaters, 1962-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Trolley Cars, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Western Views, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Williamsburg Bridge, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Williamsburg Savings Bank, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Yosemite Valley, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hasidim of Williamsburg: Boys, Buildings, 1962-1970 (Box 81)
    - Hasidim of Williamsburg: Businesses, Children, Girls, Holidays, 1962-1970 (Box 81)
    - Hasidim of Williamsburg: Men, Purim, 1962-1970 (Box 82)
    - Hasidim of Williamsburg: Schools, Weddings, Women, 1962-1970 (Box 82)
  - Sub-series: 1.2: 11x14 Photographs
    - Street Scenes, 1961-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1-13)
    - Street Scenes, 1957-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
    - Coney Island, 1959-1976 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Coney Island, 1955-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-13)
    - Coney Island, 1955-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1-12)
    - Coney Island, 1958-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1-14)
    - Coney Island, circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
    - Coney Island, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Coney Island, 1958-1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Coney Island, circa 1961-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, Architecture, 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Portraits, Street Scenes, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
    - Architecture, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Portraits, 1958-1965 (Box 10, Folder 14-17)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Israel, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4-12)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 12, Folder 1-11)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1990 (Box 13, Folder 5-12)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1990 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1970 (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1990 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Matzo Bakery, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Matzo Bakery, Lee Avenue, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Weddings, Signs, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Signs, Religious Institutes, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Religious Institutes, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, Sukkos, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6-11)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Kapparot, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Wedding, Succos, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Wedding, Funeral, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Street Scenes, Religious Institutes, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Camp, Purim, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Classroom, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Museum Prints, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Classroom, Sukkos, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Torah Dedication, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Shloma Weiss the Baker, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Lee Avenue, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Torah Restoration, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Torah Restoration, Matzoh, Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Portraits, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Museum Prints: Simchas Torah, Wedding, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Faces Across the Aisle: Subway Glimpses, circa 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 1-14)
    - Subway Glimpses, circa 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Travel, Ocean Parkway, Street Scene, circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 3-15)
    - Yosemite National Park, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
    - Yosemite National Park, circa 1970 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
    - Library Scenes, Egypt, circa 1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Egypt, crica 1970 (Box 20, Folder 5-12)
    - Egypt, circa 1970 (Box 21, Folder 1-5)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1975 (Box 21, Folder 6-9)
    - Architecture, Beach, circa 1975 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Landscape, Nature, circa 1975 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Portraits, Still Life, circa 1975 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Coney Island, Still Life, circa 1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Portraits, Prospect Park, 1962-1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Architecture, Hot Air Balloons, Portraits, circa 1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Nature, Portraits, circa 1985 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, circa 1985 (Box 22, Folder 5-6)
    - Portraits, circa 1975 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-1970 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
    - Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
    - Architecture, Portraits, 1952-1956 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Architecture, Portraits, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Architecture, Portraits, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1958 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Nature, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Nature, Portraits, circa 1960-1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Travel, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Travel, circa 1970-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Landscape, Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, Still Life, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Animals, Architecture, circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Portraits, Still Life, circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
    - Portraits, circa 1956-1960 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
    - Architecture, Still Life, Travel, circa 1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Architecture, circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Museum, Brooklyn Public Library, circa 1970 (Box 25, Folder 3-7)
  - Sub-series: 1.3: Oversize Photographs and Exhibit Materials
    - Portraits, circa 195-1960 (Box 26, Folder 1-5)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1950-1970 (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
    - Architecture, Landscape, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 27, Folder 1-5)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Architecture, circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Architecture, Nature, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Architecture, Still Life, circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Israel, Hasidim of Williamsburg, circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 5-8)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 29, Folder 1-4)
    - Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-1970 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Animals, Landscape, Streetscape, circa 1970 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Architecture, Landscape, circa 1955 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Architecture, circa 1975 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Architecture, Landscape, circa 1975 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Cityscape, Landscape, circa 1950 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Architecture, Cityscape, circa 1950-1970 (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
    - Portraits, circa 1955 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
    - Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, Street Scenes, circa 1960 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Cityscape, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Architecture, Landscape, circa 1950-1970 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Portraits, circa 1955-1960 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Portraits, circa 1960-1970 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, Visions of Brooklyn Exhibit Materials, circa 1960, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Visions of Brooklyn Exhibit Materials, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Exhibit Materials, Various, circa 1950-1980 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    - Portraits, circa 1950 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-1969 (Box 33, Folder 2-5)
    - Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Portraits, circa 1950 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-1980 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Portraits, circa 1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Cityscapes, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
    - Architecture, Portraits, circa 1960 (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Slides
  - California, Canada, Colorado, Pacific Northwest, Utah, Wyoming, circa 1970 (Box 35)
  - Colorado, France, Germany, Oregon, Switzerland, circa 1970 (Box 36)
  - Egypt, Grand Canyon, New Mexico, circa 1970 (Box 37)
  - Atlantic Antic, Canada, Feast of St. Gennaro, New England, Niagra Falls, Pennsylvania, circa 1970 (Box 38)
  - Portraits, Purim, Travel, circa 1970 (Box 39)
  - Festivals, Florida, Maine, New York, circa 1970 (Box 40)
  - California, Egypt, Grand Canyon, Israel, circa 1970 (Box 41)
  - California, Pacific Northwest, circa 1970 (Box 42)
  - Egypt, Israel, circa 1970 (Box 43)
  - New York, Portraits, circa 1970 (Box 44)
- Series 3: Negatives
  - #3-88, unnumbered, 1949-1951 (Box 45)
  - #90-165, 1951-1952 (Box 46)
  - #166-275, 1952-1954 (Box 47)
  - #278-370, 1954-1956 (Box 48)
  - #371-426, 1956-1957 (Box 49)
  - #427-529, 1957-1958 (Box 50)
  - #530-600, 1958-1959 (Box 51)
  - #603-734, 1959-1960 (Box 52)
  - #735-795, 1960-1961 (Box 53)
  - #796-920, 1961-1962 (Box 54)
  - #921-1090, 1962-1964 (Box 55)
  - #1091-1206, 1964-1965 (Box 56)
  - #1208-1273, 1965-1966 (Box 57)
  - #1274-1349, 1966-1967 (Box 58)
  - #1350-1407, 1967-1968 (Box 59)
  - #1408-1454, 1968-1969 (Box 60)
  - #1455-1517, 1969-1970 (Box 61)
  - #1518-1585, 1970-1971 (Box 62)
  - #1586-1636, 1971-1972 (Box 63)
  - #1637-1706, 1972-1973 (Box 64)
  - #1707-1771, 1973-1974 (Box 65)
  - #1773-1819, 1974 (Box 66)
  - #1820-1868, 1974-1976 (Box 67)
  - #1869-1925, 1976-1977 (Box 68)
  - #1926-1973, 1977-1978 (Box 69)
  - #1974-2021, 1978 (Box 70)
  - #2022-2071, 1978-1979 (Box 71)
  - #2072-2121, 1979-1980 (Box 72)
  - #-2140-2167, 1980-1981 (Box 73)
  - #2168-2215, 1981 (Box 74)
  - #2216-2265, 1981-1983 (Box 75)
  - #2264-2311, 1983-1984 (Box 76)
  - #2312-2355, 1984-1986 (Box 77)
  - #2356-2395, 1986-1988 (Box 78)
  - #2396-2434, unnumbered, 1988-1991 (Box 79)
- Series 4: Audiovisual
  - "America the Beautiful", circa 1970 (Box 80, Cassette 1-4)
  - "Egypt Land of the Pharaohs", circa 1970 (Box 80, Cassette 5-6)
  - "Europe Revisited, In Search of Roots", 1978 (Box 80, Cassette 7-10)
  - "Miami, Tropical Paradise", circa 1970 (Box 80, Cassette 11)
  - "New Mexico and Canyonlands", 1984 (Box 80, Cassette 12-15)
  - "Pacific Northwest, Canadian Rockies", circa 1970 (Box 80, Cassette 16-17)
- Series 5: Documents
  - Clippings and Publications, 1954-1984, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1977, 1995, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Exhibits, 1965-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Index, Coney Island: My Backyard (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Index, Faces Across the Aisle: Subway Glimpses (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Index, The Hasidim of Williamsburg (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Index, Jewish Life of Ocean Avenue (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Index, Prints Held by the Jewish Museum (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Index, Small Projects (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Irving Herzberg: A Vision of Brooklyn (1950-1989), Exhibit Materials, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Irving Herzberg: A Vision of Brooklyn (1950-1989), Invitations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Irving Herzberg: A Vision of Brooklyn (1950-1989), Promotional Materials, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)